# Joonas Suuronen

I am 24-year-old Information and Communication Technology Engineer, I always have had a huge passion for technology and science. Especially computers and programming have always fascinated me. I constantly develop various ICT-projects like video games, web sites or even embedded systems. I often achieve a flow state in these projects, and I might spend over 14 hours in a row. This reminds me of a quote: "Choose a job you love and you'll never have to work a day in your life" - Confucius.





isuuronen9@gmail.com



+358 400368833



📍 Espoo, Suomi



www.banaanigames.com/

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Software Developer** Metropolia, SAM-project

01/2022 - 11/2022

Began with my thesis, but I was hired to continue. To simplify, the project was about creating an application for simulation of surveillance of autonomus vehicles

#### Details

- UI / UX Development
- Team management
- Other various tasks

Contact: Pekko Lindblom, project manager pekko.lindblom@metropolia.fi, +358 504733152

### **Game Developer**

### Net Get Games (formerly Tutanet Oy)

05/2020 - 07/2022

Few developers worked on game called "News Reacts". I was hired to develop the UI and some core mechanics. The game shipped to Steam in

#### Details

- UI / UX
- Core Mechanics
- Optimization

Contact: Jukka Soinila, CEO jukka.soinila@gmail.com, +358 415015856

### **Security Guard** Avarn Security

05/2017 - Present

#### Details

- Security services in many forms
- Due to years of good work, I have been trusted more advanced job types and introducing new employees
- Starting from 2022, mostly includes driving Nokia 5G vans

# **EDUCATION**

Information and Communication Technology Metropolia Unviversity of Applied Sciences

08/2018 - 11/2022

### **Matriculation examination** Leppävaara Upper Secondary School

08/2014 - 06/2017

### **SKILLS**

Programming

Image & Audio

AI and ML

### **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

You can find most of my significant projects in here: https://www.banaanigames.com/showcase.html

- Homewide adblock system with Raspberry Pi
- SAM Project (engineer's thesis + paid continuation)
- News Reacts (job as a game developer)
- ML / AI Director with Python, visualization and data handling
- OpenGL rendering engine with C++ and few libraries
- Nords and Swrods game project
- Chess with really strong AI with C++ and minimax algorithm
- Collision detection engine with Python and few libraries
- Grainraiders game project
- "Sumo robot" programming and data connection with C and PuTTy (embedded systems + IoT project)

## **LANGUAGES**

Finnish

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

Swedish

German

Limited Working Proficiency

Limited Working Proficiency

### INTERESTS

Technology Programming Video Games

Science

Gym

Mathematics

**Physics**